<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest News | DIPr Lab at PSU</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Latest News</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/icon_hu11534601174274055989.png</url>
      <title>Latest News</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>CyberPDX 2024</title>
      <link>/post/07-29-24-cyberpdx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/07-29-24-cyberpdx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About CyberPDX:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CyberPDX is a no-cost 5-day residential summer STEAM camp hosted at the Portland State University Maseeh College of Engineering &amp;amp; Computer Science. This year&amp;rsquo;s camp is designed for Native and Indigenous high school students to introduce them to cybersecurity skills, principles, policies, and careers through an interactive STEAM curriculum and career exposure. All are welcome. The camp activities will be led by many PSU faculty and local experts, which includes local Indigenous leaders. This is an incredible opportunity for Native and Indigenous students to get an immersive, interdisciplinary, and fun experience on a college campus. No prior experience is necessary, and beginners are welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year&amp;rsquo;s CyberPDX had threads on Cryptography, Programming, Privacy, Policy and Film. &lt;a href=&#34;/author/primal-pappachan/&#34;&gt;Primal Pappachan&lt;/a&gt; was the instructor for the Privacy thread and &lt;a href=&#34;/author/dylan-conklin/&#34;&gt;Dylan Conklin&lt;/a&gt; was the Teaching Assistant. The topics covered in this thread include&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Importance of Privacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Difference between Privacy and Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debating risk versus convenience of app features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading Privacy Policies of Social Media Applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming in Python to use Generative AI as a Privacy Assistant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about, please check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pdx.edu/engineering/cyberpdx-cybersecurity-camp-native-indigenous-high-school-students&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CyberPDX website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPE presentation - Anadi Shakya</title>
      <link>/post/06-21-24-anadi-rpe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/06-21-24-anadi-rpe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/author/anadi-shakya/&#34;&gt;Anadi Shakya&lt;/a&gt; successfully completed the oral part of her Research Profiency Examination (RPE) on &lt;strong&gt;‘Sieve and Cache: Scalable Access Control for Dynamic IoT Applications’&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Committee Members&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;/author/primal-pappachan/&#34;&gt;Primal Pappachan&lt;/a&gt; (Portland State University) ; Dave Maier (Portland State University) ; Wu-chang Feng (Portland State University)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: The proliferation of smart technologies and newer privacy regulations necessitate effective management of user preferences about data sharing using access control policies. Current Database Management Systems (DBMS) struggle to efficiently answer queries while enforcing a large number of Fine-Grained Access Control (FGAC) policies. Sieve is a middleware for relational DBMSs that generate guarded expressions, which are efficient rewriting of queries with a given set of policies. In this paper, we extend Sieve with caching of guarded expressions to better handle dynamic workloads involving a series of policy insertions and queries at different frequencies. Our novel caching approach includes a replacement policy based on clock algorithm and a refresh strategy based on cost analysis to select between regeneration and update of guarded expressions. We also develop a workload generator that creates different workloads with different distributions of policies, and queries that are relevant to a chosen scenario. These workloads simulate realistic IoT scenarios, such as smart campus applications. Experimental results show that Sieve, enhanced with caching, is effective in terms of cache-hits and efficient in terms of system load and latency of query answering, in dynamic environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIPr Lab at 2024 Summer Research Academy (SRA)</title>
      <link>/post/06-21-24-sra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/06-21-24-sra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summer Research Academy (SRA) is designed to engage undergraduate students interested in making a difference in
their communities by pursuing research opportunities in STEM, biomedical, behavioral, clinical, health, and social
sciences.  Students do not have to have prior research experience to participate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DIPr lab had a table at SRA 2024 with the following members attending (from left to right): &lt;a href=&#34;/author/nicholas-g.e.-morales/&#34;&gt;Nicholas G.E. Morales&lt;/a&gt;, Michael Howard, &lt;a href=&#34;/author/satvik-mudgal/&#34;&gt;Satvik Mudgal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/author/steve-willoughby/&#34;&gt;Steve Willoughby&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/author/primal-pappachan/&#34;&gt;Primal Pappachan&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;/author/dylan-conklin/&#34;&gt;Dylan Conklin&lt;/a&gt;. We had many interested undergraduates stop by our table to learn about our various research projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about, please check out their website &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/pdx.edu/2024-sra/home-page?authuser=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2024 SRA website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to DIPr lab at PSU</title>
      <link>/post/21-01-24-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-01-24-launch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Database &amp;amp; Internet Privacy Lab offically starts at the Portland State University. We are a diverse group of researchers studying problems in user privacy, data management, access control, differential privacy, systems, algorithms, and privacy regulations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
